Register of the Kurt Richard Grossmann Papers, 1913-1973
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, c.1933-1972 (Box 16-36)
  - "Vietnamkrieg beenden?" (V. war to end?), Tagwacht, Printed copy., September 3, 1970. (Folder 35: 45)
  - "Ein Volk gespalten," (A people divided), Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copy., May 20, 1970. (Folder 35: 46)
  - "Das Volk verlaesst den Praesidenten," (The people abandon the president), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., October 12, 1967. (Folder 35: 47)
  - "Eines Volkes Erinnerung ist seine Geschichte," (The memory of a people is its history), Aufbau, Printed copy., April 29, 1960. (Folder 35: 48)
  - "Vom finanziellen Volumen," Aufbau, Printed copy., February 21, 1964. (Folder 35: 49)
  - "Vom garnicht goldnen Wiener Herzen," (About the not so golden Viennese heart), Aufbau, Reprints., February 3, 1961. (Folder 35: 50)
  - "Von der Mauer zum Kurfuerstendamm," (From the wall to K.), Neue Presse, Printed copy. (Folder 35: 51)
  - "Von draussen gesehen," (As seen from the outside), Telegraf, Printed copy., January 6, 1960. (Folder 35: 52)
  - "Von Gerlach zum Gedenken," (In memory of von Gerlach), Semana Israelita, Printed copy., March 4, 1966. (Folder 35: 53)
  - "Von Grenze zu Grenze, Augenzeugen berichten aus Jugoslavien," (From border to border, witnesses report from Yugoslavia), Aufbau, Printed copy., February 5, 1943. (Folder 35: 54)
  - "Von Rusk zu Rogers," Tagwacht, Printed copy., January 145, 1968. (Folder 35: 55)
  - "Vor dem Wiedergutmachungs-Schlussgesetz," (Before the final restitution law), Aufbau, Printed copy., March 22, 1963. (Folder 35: 56)
  - "Die Vorbereitungen fuer die Ausfuehrung des Bundesentschaedigungs-Schlussgesetzes," (The preparations for the implementation of the German final restitution law), Aufbau, Printed copy., December 3, 1965. (Folder 35: 57)
  - "Die Wage der Justitia verliert ihr Gleichgewicht," (The scales of justice lose their equilibrium), Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 35: 58)
  - "Wahlergebnis 1971 in den USA," (Election results 1971 in the US). (Folder 35: 59)
  - "Der Wahlkampf fuer 1972 hat begonnen," (The election campaign for 192 has begun), Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., February 5, 1971. (Folder 35: 60)
  - "Der Wahlkampf hat schon wieder begonnen," (The election campaign has already begun again), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., January 15, 1970. (Folder 35: 61)
  - "Wahlkampf-Schatten, Humphrey will geschichtliche Tradition durchbrechen," (Campaign shadows, H. intends to break with historical tradition), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., September 12, 1968. (Folder 35: 62)
  - "Wahlparole Gesetz und Ordnung," (Campaign slogan law and order), Tagwacht, Printed copy., September 18, 1971. (Folder 35: 63)
  - "Waehrend Millionen starben, Enthuellungen ueber die Rettungs versuche der Juden," (While millions died, revelations about the attempts to rescue the Jews), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., March 14, 1968. (Folder 35: 64)
  - "Die Wahrheit ist unbequem," (Truth is uncomfortable), Westfaelische Rundschau, Printed copy., February 16, 1960. (Folder 35: 65)
  - "Die Wahrheit ueber den Fall Kastner," (The truth about the Kastner case), Aufbau, Printed copy., July 19, 1955. (Folder 35: 66)
  - "Wall des Schweigens," (Wall of silence), Aufbau, Printed copy., Secember 10, 1965. (Folder 35: 67)
  - "Wallace siegt in Alabama," (W. wins in Alabama), Tagwacht, Printed copy., June 9, 1970. (Folder 35: 68)
  - "Walter Reuthers Tod: Ein unersetzlicher Verlust," (W. R.'s death, an unreplacable loss), Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 35: 69)
  - "War Refugee Board," Encyclopaedia Judaica, Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 35: 70)
  - "Warten auf Johnson," (Waiting for J.), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., June 1, 1967. (Folder 35: 71)
  - "Warum wurde Nixon sein eigener David Ellsberg?" (Why did N. become his own D. E.?), Typescript (carbon copy)., February 1, 1972. (Folder 35: 72)
  - "Was bedeutet der Sieg Nixons?" (What is the meaning of N.'s victory?), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., November 14, 1968. (Folder 35: 73)
  - "Was ist mit der Widergutmachung?" (What is going on with the restitution program?), Rheinischer Merkur, Printed copy., February 7, 1958. (Folder 35: 74)
  - "Was Nixon schwaecht, Rassist Wallace wieder auf dem Sprungbrett zur Macht," (What is weakening N., racist W. again on the springboard to power), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., June 25, 1970. (Folder 35: 75)
  - "Washington aendert seine China-Politik," (W. is changing its China policy), Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 35: 76)
  - "Weder Vorurteile noch Illusionen," (Neither prejudice nor illusion), Rheinischer Merkur, Printed copy., n.d. (Folder 35: 77)
  - "Der Weg nach Israel," (The road to I.), Rheinischer Merkur, Printed copy., November 22, 1968. (Folder 35: 78)
  - "Wege der Rettung," (Ways of being saved), Aufbau, Printed copy., February 16, 1945. (Folder 35: 79)
  - "Weglaufen ist keine Loesung fuer das USA Dilemma," (Running away is no solution for the American dilemma), Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 35: 80)
  - "Wegweisende Selstkritik?" (Constructive self criticism?), Tagwacht, Printed copy., July 5, 1971. (Folder 35: 81)
  - "Die Weichen werden auf 1972 umgestellt," (The tracks are being redirected for 1972), Typescript (carbon copy)., November 10, 1970. (Folder 35: 82)
  - "Weimar und Washington, Pflicht zum Landesverrat in den USA," (W. and W., the duty to treason in the US), Tagwacht, Printed copy., June 26, 1971. (Folder 35: 83)
  - "Das Weisse Haus spielt russische Roulette," (The White House plays Russian roulette), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., March 12, 1971. (Folder 35: 84)
  - "Eine Wende muss kommen," (There must be a change), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., January 2, 1969. (Folder 36: 1)
  - "Wenn ich ein Neger waere," (If I were black), Tagwacht, Printed copy., May 25, 1970. (Folder 36: 2)
  - "Wenn Steine reden," (If stones could speak), Aufbau, Printed copy., July 3, 1964. (Folder 36: 3)
  - "Wer wird Buergermeister von Neuyork?" (Who will be mayor of New York?), Tagwacht, Printed copy., October 10, 1969. (Folder 36: 4)
  - "Werden die Fluechtlinge in Nordafrika frei?" (Will the refugees in North Africa be free?), Aufbau, Printed copy., January 22, 1943. (Folder 36: 5)
  - "Werden die Rententabellen korrigiert?" (Will the pension tables be corrected?), Aufbau, Printed copy., March 25, 1966. (Folder 36: 6)
  - "Werner Marx, 60jaehrig," Aufbau, Printed copy., September 11, 1970. (Folder 36: 7)
  - "West German Press Opinion on Israel," Mimeographed copies., n.d. (Folder 36: 8)
  - "Wettlauf ins Weisse Haus," (Race to the White House), Vorwaerts, Printed copies., March 7, 1968. (Folder 36: 9)
  - "Der Wettlauf mit dem Tode," (Race with death), Telegraf, Printed copy., May 26, 1957. (Folder 36: 10)
  - "Der Wettlauf nach dem Mond und die Raealitaeten auf der Erde," (The race to the moon and the realities on earth), Typescript (carbon copy)., July 15, 1969. (Folder 36: 11)
  - "What Were the Jewish Losses?" Congress Weekly, Printed copy., October 12, 1953. (Folder 36: 12)
  - "Why Israel Can Grow," Congress Weekly, Printed copy., February 21, 1949. (Folder 36: 13)
  - "Eine wichtige Entscheidung fuer Naziopfer aus Oesterreich," (An important decision for Nazi victims from Austria), Aufbau, Printed copy., September 23, 1966. (Folder 36: 14)
  - "Widersprueche, Parteidisziplin, Gewissensentscheidung," (Contradictions, party discipline, decisions of conscience), Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 36: 15)
  - "Widerstandskaempfer in juedisher Sicht," (Resistance fighters in the Jewish view), Typescript notes. (Folder 36: 16)
  - "Wie das Bundesentschaedigungsgesetz durchgefuehrt wird," (How the German restitution law will be implimented), Aufbau, Reprints. (Folder 36: 17)
  - "Wie hoch sind die wirklichen juedischen Verluste?" (How high are the actual Jewish losses?), Israelitisches Wochenblatt, Printed copy., July 10, 1959. (Folder 36: 18)
  - "Wie stark ist Nixon?" (How strong is N.?), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., August 21, 1969. (Folder 36: 19)
  - "Wie steht es mit der Wiedergutmachung, geloeste und ungeloeste Probleme," (How is the restitution program working? Solved and unsolved problems), Rheinischer Merkur, Reprint., March 24, 1961. (Folder 36: 20)
  - "Die Wiedergutmachung," (Restitution), Geist und Tat, Printed copies., April 1961. (Folder 36: 21)
  - "Wiedergutmachung, echter Rechtsanspruch," (Restitution, valid legal demand), Das Beste aus gestern und heute, Printed copies., June 1964. (Folder 36: 22)
  - "Die Wiedergutmachung ist nicht beendet," (Restitution is not ended), Aufbau, Printed copy., November 9, 1962. (Folder 36: 23)
  - "Wiedergutmachungssorgen und Neuigkeiten," (Restitution worries and news), Aufbau, Typescript and printed copies., February 9, 1968. (Folder 36: 24)
  - "Wiedergutmachungswerk nicht beendet!" (Restitution work not over!), Printed copy., January 24, 1969. (Folder 36: 25)
  - "Wiederholt sich das Johnson Wunder?" (Will the J. miracle be repeated?), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., June 25, 1971. (Folder 36: 26)
  - "Wiederholt sich 1929 im Jahre 1970?" (Will 1929 be repeated in the year 1970?), Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copy., June 1, 1970. (Folder 36: 27)
  - "Wiedersehen mit der Tschechoslowakei nach dreissig Jahren," (Return to Czechoslovakia after 30 years), Tribuene, Printed copy., 1968. (Folder 36: 28)
  - "Wieviel Juden leben in der Welt?" (How many Jews live in the world?), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., June 1953. (Folder 36: 29)
  - "Wilhelm Friedrich Foerster und die Deutschen," (W.F.F. and the Germans), Die Friedensrundschau, Printed copies., 1966. (Folder 36: 30)
  - "Willy Brandt, der Mann des Jahres," (W.B. man of the year), Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copy., January 6, 1971. (Folder 36: 31)
  - "Willy Brandt und der Friedensnobelpreis, Erinnerung un Erfuellung," (W.B. and the Nobel peace prize, remembrance and fulfillment), Die Mahnung, Typescript and printed copies., December 15, 1971. (Folder 36: 32)
  - "Willy Brandt und seine Ostpolitik," (W.B. and his policy toward Eastern Europe), Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 36: 33)
  - "Wirtschaft, Aussen- und Innenpolitik," (The economy, foreign and domestic policy), Boletin informativo, Typescript and printed copy., November 1971. (Folder 36: 34)
  - "Die Wirtschaftgewaltigen haven Misstrauen gegen Nixon," (Financiers distrust N.), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., June 7, 1970. (Folder 36: 35)
  - "Wirtschaftliche Probleme in USA," (Economic problems in the US), Tagwacht, Printed copy., October 21, 1971. (Folder 36: 36)
  - "Wolken am deutschen Himmel?" (Clouds in the German sky?), Tagwacht, Printed copy., October 1, 1971. (Folder 36: 37)
  - "Ein Zeichner der Zeit," (An artist of the time), Aufbau, Printed copy., April 7, 1961. (Folder 36: 38)
  - "Die Zeit ist ueber sie hinweggegangen, die Bundestagsdebatte ueber das Schlussgesetz," (Time has passed them by, debate in parliament on the final law) Aufbau, Printed copy., June 11, 1965. (Folder 36: 39)
  - "Zerstoerte Hoffnungen, Tragoedien der Wiedergutmachung," (Dashed hopes, tragedies of restitution), Aufbau, Printed copy., July 16, 1954. (Folder 36: 40)
  - "Zeugnisse der Menschlichkeit, warum ich Die unbesungenen Helden schrieb," (Documents of human kindness, why I wrote The Unsung Heroes), Telegraf, Typescript and printed copies., June 4, 1961. (Folder 36: 41)
  - "Zionists and Non-Zionists Under the Nazi Rule in the 1930's," Herzl Year Book, Printed copy., 1961. (Folder 36: 42)
  - "Zukunft und Gegenwart des Engschaedigungs-programs," (Present and future of the restitution program), Printed copy., September 20, 1963. (Folder 36: 43)
  - "Zum Nachteil veraendert? Ein Beobachter aus Amerika berichtet von einer Reise durch die Bundesrepublik," (Changed for the worse? An Observer from America reports on a trip through West Germany), Rheinischer Merkur, Printed copy., January 21, 1966. (Folder 36: 44)
  - "Zum siebzigsten Geburtstag von Adolf Leschnitzer," (On the 70th birthday of A. L.), Aufbau, Printed copy., January 31, 1969. (Folder 36: 45)
  - "Zum Tode von Marcel Schulte," (On the death of M.S.), Aufbau, Printed copy., October 29, 1965. (Folder 36: 46)
  - "Zur Problematik der KZ Liste," (On the problems of the camplist), Aufbau, Printed copy., October 10, 1969. (Folder 36: 47)
  - "Zwanzig Jahre Kampf fuer die Menschenrechte," (Twenty year struggle for human rights), Types cript and carbon copy., c. 1940. (Folder 36: 48)
  - "Zweimal Amerika, die USA zerfallen in zwei Gesellschaften," (US is dividing into two societies), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., March 14, 1968. (Folder 36: 49)
  - "Der zweitschwerste Posten, J.V. Lindsay kaempft hart um seine Wiederwahl Buergermeister von N.Y.," (The second most difficult job, J.V.L. fights hard for his reelection as mayor of N.Y.), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., October 16, 1969. (Folder 36: 50)
- SUBJECT FILE, c. 1933-1972. (Box 37-60)
  Articles, clippings, correspondence, and writings by others collected by Kurt R. Grossmann, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Abramovitch, Raphael. (Folder 37: 1)
  - American Council for Equal Compensation of Nazi Victims from Austria (ACOA).
    - General. (Folder 37: 2-5)
    - 1966. (Folder 37: 6)
    - 1967. (Folder 37: 7)
    - 1968. (Folder 37: 8)
    - 1969. (Folder 37: 9)
    - 1970. (Folder 37: 10)
    - 1971. (Folder 37: 11)
    - Correspondence.
      - General. (Folder 37: 12)
      - Austria. (Folder 37: 13)
      - Harding, Felix. (Folder 37: 14)
      - United States. (Folder 37: 15)
      - Wegner, Henry. (Folder 38: 1)
      - West Germany. (Folder 38: 2)
  - Anti-Semitism. (Folder 38: 3)
  - Aufbau.
    - 1940. (Folder 38: 4)
    - 1941. (Folder 38: 5)
    - 1942. (Folder 38: 6)
    - 1943. (Folder 38: 7)
    - 1945. (Folder 38: 8)
    - 1957. (Folder 38: 9)
    - 1960. (Folder 38: 10)
    - 1961. (Folder 38: 11)
    - 1962. (Folder 38: 12)
    - 1963. (Folder 38: 13)
    - 1964. (Folder 38: 14)
    - 1965. (Folder 38: 15)
    - 1966. (Folder 38: 16)
    - 1967. (Folder 38: 17)
    - 1969. (Folder 38: 18)
    - 1970. (Folder 38: 19)
  - Bauer, Leo. (Folder 39: 1)
  - Berlin Festschrift Committee (see also SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, Gegenwart im Rueckblick)
    - General. (Folder 39: 2-3)
    - Kurt Tucholsky Archiv. (Folder 39: 4)
    - Lothar Stiehm Verlag. (Folder 39: 5)
  - Brandt, Willy. (Folder 39: 6-11)
  - Conference on Jewish Material Claims Against Germany (Claims Conference).
    - General. (Folder 39: 12-15)
    - (Franz Boehm Memorandum)., 1957 (Folder 39: 16)
    - 1964. (Folder 40: 1)
    - 1965. (Folder 40: 2)
    - 1966. (Folder 40: 3)
    - 1967. (Folder 40: 4)
    - 1968. (Folder 40: 5)
    - 1969. (Folder 40: 6-7)
    - 1970. (Folder 40: 8)
    - 1970. (Folder 41: 1-3)
    - 1971. (Folder 41: 4-7)
    - 1972. (Folder 41: 8)
  - Czechoslovakia. (Folder 41: 9)
  - Defregger, Mathias. (Folder 41: 10)
  - Demokratische Fluechtlingsfuersorge. (Folder 41: 11-14)
  - Demokratische Fluechtlingsfuersorge. (Folder 42: 1-5)
  - Deutsch, Hans. (Folder 42: 6)
  - Deutsche Liga fuer Menschenrechte.
    - General. (Folder 42: 7-9)
    - Bund Neues Vaterland (previous name).
      - General. (Folder 42: 10)
      - Ein Bekenntnis deutscher Schuld (A confession of German guilt). (Folder 42: 11)
      - Durch zum Rechtsfrieden (On to peace under law). (Folder 42: 12)
      - Durch zur Wahrheit (On to truth). (Folder 42: 13)
      - England und der Krieg (England and the war). (Folder 42: 14)
      - Hans Paasche. (Folder 42: 15)
      - Meine Londoner Mission. (Folder 42: 16)
      - Michel wach auf! (German awake!). (Folder 42: 17)
      - Mitteilungen (Announcements). (Folder 42: 18)
      - Rennsport und Englaenderei (Horse racing and the British). (Folder 42: 19)
      - Satzungen (rules). (Folder 42: 20)
      - Schuld und Suenhe (Guilt and reconciliation). (Folder 42: 21)
      - Treibende Kraefte (Driving forces). (Folder 42: 22)
      - Vier Jahre Luege (4 years of lies). (Folder 42: 23)
      - Was taete Bismarck (What would Bismarck do?). (Folder 42: 24)
      - Was will der Bund Neues Vaterland? (What does the Bund want?). (Folder 42: 25)
      - Die Wurzeln der Politik Wilsons (The roots of W.'s policy). (Folder 42: 26)
      - Zur Beurteilung der deutschen Kriegsfuehrung (Assessment of the German conduct of war). (Folder 42: 27)
      - Der Zusammenbruch der deutschen Polenpolitik (The collapse of the German Polish policy). (Folder 42: 28)
    - Gerlach Hellmut von. (Folder 43: 1)
    - Gumbel, E. J. (Folder 43: 2)
    - Kahn Emile. (Folder 43: 3)
    - Die Menschenrechte (Human rights).
      - 1926. (Folder 43: 4-5)
      - 1927. (Folder 43: 6)
      - 1928. (Folder 43: 7-8)
      - 1929. (Folder 43: 9-10, Folder 44: 1-2)
      - 1930. (Folder 44: 3-5)
      - 1931. (Folder 44: 6-7)
      - 1932. (Folder 44: 8-10)
    - Publications (as Deutsche Liga).
      - Der Fall Quidde (The Quidde case). (Folder 45: 1)
      - Krieg dem Kriege (War on war). (Folder 45: 2)
      - Das Stahlbad des Krieges (The steel bath of war). (Folder 45: 3)
      - Victor Basch in Potsdam. (Folder 45: 4)
      - Wenn Friedensfreunde reden (When advocates of peace speak). (Folder 45: 5)
  - Deutsche National-Zeitung. (Folder 45: 6-7)
  - Digest on Germany and Austria.
    - 1960. (Folder 45: 8)
    - 1961. (Folder 45: 9)
    - 1962. (Folder 45: 10)
    - 1963. (Folder 45: 11)
    - 1965. (Folder 45: 12)
  - Eichmann, Adolf. (Folder 45: 13)
  - Einstein Haus, Ulm. (Folder 45: 14)
  - Der europaeische Staatenbund. (Folder 45: 15)
  - European Federation, proposal, 1939. (Folder 45: 16, Folder 46: 1)
  - "Der Fall Peter Zenger," by Gerd, Hermann Boettger. (Folder 46: 2)
  - "Der Fall Jakubowski," CCC television, Berlin. (Folder 46: 3)
  - Freiheit und Recht. (Folder 46: 4)
  - Geneva Conventions for the Protection of War Victims. (Folder 46: 5)
  - German refugees from Czechoslovakia, 1939. (Folder 46: 6)
  - German refugees in Czechoslovakia, 1938. (Folder 46: 7-8)
  - Germans in the United States. (Folder 46: 9)
  - Germany.
    - Foreign relations. (Folder 46: 10)
    - National Socialism. (Folder 46: 11-13, Folder 47: 1-2)
    - Political resistance. (Folder 47: 3)
  - Germany, East. (Folder 47: 4-7)
  - Germany, West.
    - Neo-Nazi movements. (Folder 47: 8)
    - German-Polish treaty, 1970. (Folder 47: 9)
    - Politics and government. (Folder 47: 10, Folder 48: 1-4)
    - Prosecution of war criminals. (Folder 48: 5-6)
    - Statute of limitations on war crimes. (Folder 48: 7-8)
  - Grossmann, Elsa. (Folder 48: 9-11, Folder 49: 1-4)
  - Hilfsverein der Juden in Deutschland. (Folder 49: 5-8)
  - Hillgruber. (Folder 49: 9)
  - Hochhuth, Rolf, Der Stellvertreter. (Folder 49: 10-11)
  - Immigration. (Folder 49: 12)
  - Indiana Patriotic Publications. (Folder 49: 13)
  - International Red Cross. (Folder 49: 14)
  - International Rescue Committee. (Folder 50: 1)
  - Internationales Dokumentationszentrum zur Erforschung des Nationalsozialismus. (Folder 50: 2)
  - Israel. (Folder 50: 3)
  - Jewish Agency for Israel, Press Digest.
    - 1952. (Folder 50: 4-5)
    - 1953. (Folder 50: 6)
    - 1954. (Folder 50: 7)
    - 1955. (Folder 50: 8)
    - 1956. (Folder 50: 9)
    - 1957. (Folder 50: 10)
    - 1958. (Folder 50: 11)
    - 1959. (Folder 50: 12)
  - Jews in Czechoslovakia. (Folder 50: 13)
  - Jews in Germany. (Folder 50: 14, Folder 51: 1-3)
  - Jews in Poland. (Folder 51: 4)
  - Jews in Russia. (Folder 51: 5)
  - Jews in the United States. (Folder 51: 6)
  - Jordan, Charles. (Folder 51: 7)
  - Kempner, Robert W.M. (Folder 51: 8)
  - Kiesinger, Kurt Georg. (Folder 51: 9)
  - Korherr, Richard. (Folder 51: 10)
  - Krause, Franz. (Folder 51: 11)
  - Leo Baeck Institute. (Folder 51: 12)
  - LBI News. (Folder 51: 13)
  - Literature.
    - General. (Folder 51: 14)
    - Literature in exile. (Folder 51: 15)
  - Medical Research Foundation. (Folder 52: 1-5)
  - Meinecke, Georg.
    - 1967. (Folder 52: 6)
    - 1968. (Folder 52: 7)
    - 1969. (Folder 52: 8-9)
    - 1970. (Folder 52: 10-11)
    - 1971. (Folder 53: 1)
    - 1972. (Folder 53: 2-3)
    - 1973. (Folder 53: 4)
  - Miscellaneous clippings. (Folder 53: 5-10)
  - Mitscherlich, Alexander. (Folder 53: 11)
  - Nach dem Krieg, Schriften zur Neuorientierung der auswaertigen Politik. (Folder 54: 1)
  - New York Staats-Zeitung und Herold. (Folder 54: 2)
  - Oesterreich, Ruth (Folder 54: 3)
  - Ossietzky, Carl von. (Folder 54: 4-9)
  - PEN Zentrum deutschsprachiger Autoren im Ausland. (Folder 54: 10)
  - Press.
    - General. (Folder 54: 11)
    - German press in the United States. (Folder 54: 12)
  - Prinz, Joachim. (Folder 54: 13)
  - Refugees.
    - General. (Folder 54: 14-17, Folder 55: 1-3)
    - Colombia. (Folder 55: 4)
    - Intellectuals. (Folder 55: 5)
    - Mefkure and Jewish refugees. (Folder 55: 6)
    - United Nations (International Refugee Organization). (Folder 55: 7-8)
  - Relief work. (Folder 55: 9-10)
  - Restitution for victims of National Socialism.
    - General. (Folder 55: 11-13, Folder 56: 1)
    - Austria. (Folder 56: 2-3)
    - "German Reparations to Israel and the Jews," by F. B. Feigert. (Folder 56: 4)
    - Haushaltsicherungsgesetz, 1965-66. (Folder 56: 5-9)
    - Statistics. (Folder 56: 10)
    - Trip reports by Kurt R. Grossman regarding Wiedergut macung negotiations, 1952. (Folder 56: 11-12)
    - United Restitution Organization. (Folder 56: 13)
  - Schneider, Lambert. (Folder 57: 1)
  - Schutzverband der Schriftsteller deutscher Sprache. (Folder 57: 2-3)
  - Sommer, Robert and family members. (Folder 57: 4-22)
  - Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschland. (Folder 58: 1-4)
  - Springer, Axel. (Folder 58: 5)
  - Strauss, Franz Josef. (Folder 58: 6)
  - United States.
    - Immigration. (Folder 58: 7-12)
    - Politics and government. (Folder 59: 1-8)
    - Vietnam War. (Folder 59: 9)
  - "Unsung heroes," material relating to non-Jewish Germans who rescued Jews from National Socialist persecution.
    - General. (Folder 59: 10)
    - Reception, November 22 1967. (Folder 59: 11-16)
  - Urzidil, Johannes. (Folder 59: 17)
  - Wegner, Armin T. (Folder 60: 1)
  - Die Weltbuehne. (photocopies)
    - 1925-1931. (Folder 60: 2)
    - 1932. (Folder 60: 3)
    - 1933-1936. (Folder 60: 4)
    - 1946-1948, 1962. (Folder 60: 5)
  - World Jewish Congress. (Folder 60: 6-8)
  - World War II. (Folder 60: 9)
  - Zentralrat der Juden in Deutschland. (Folder 60: 10)
- OVERSIZE FILE (Box 61-62, 65-67)
  Seven albums containing clippings, photographs, and memorabilia relating to the life of Kurt R. Grossmann.
  - Five albums containing clippings, photographs, and memorabilia relating to the life of Kurt Grossmann. (Box 61-62, 65-67, Reel 80-81)
  - Two albums of clippings relating to Ossietzky: ein deutscher Patriot (Ossietzky: a German patriot), awarded the Albert Schweitzer book prize (Box 63, Reel 82)
- CARD FILE, undated (Box 68, Reel 81)
  Index cards arranged in two groups, (1) names, addresses, and notes; and (2) names and table numbers; thereunder by surname of person. Formerly in box 62.
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE
  42 photographs, arranged by subject, one film.
  - Photographic prints of Kurt R. Grossmann, Willy Brandt, Carl von Ossietzky, and others. 42 items (Envelope A)
  - One motion picture film reel (Film shelf)
- INCREMENT REMOVED IN NOVEMBER 1985, 1925-1962. (Box 64)
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Closed
  Die Weltbuehne, 1925-1962 (with gaps). Originals removed from box 60. Photocopies are available in box 60 for researcher use